John C. **Kegelman**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT PELOTON TECHNOLOGY

56 Sheridan St., Los Altos, CA 94022

🛮 757-593-2561 | 💌 jckegelman@gmail.com | 😭 jckegelman | 🛅 johnckegelman | 💆 @johnckegelman

Summary_

I am revolutionizing the trucking industry by making vehicles safer and more fuel efficient through automation. I contribute a deep understanding of vehicle dynamics and controls with practical experience and a great appreciation that all models are wrong, but some are useful.

Education

Stanford University Stanford, CA

Ph.D. in Mechanical Engineering

Apr. 2012–Dec. 2018

• Thesis topic: Learning from Highly-Skilled Drivers to make Automated Vehicles Safer

Stanford University Stanford, CA

M.S. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING
Sep. 2009–Apr. 2012

· Coursework focused on controls, advanced dynamics and simulation, and electromechanical design.

Johns Hopkins University

Baltimore, MD

B.S. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Sep. 2005-May 2009

• 4.0 GPA. Minored in Entrepreneurship and Management.

Experience

Peloton Technology Mountain View, CA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER May 2017–PRESENT

- Implemented a distributed safety monitoring system for a commercial platooning system following the ISO 26262 standard.
 Collected, compiled, and analyzed braking data to inform the safety of the intended functionality (SOTIF) analysis of a commercial pla-
- tooning system.

 Developed a graphical user interface in Python for vehicle data visualization and exploratory data analysis.
- Developed a graphical user interface in Python for vehicle data visualization and exploratory data analysis.
- Contributed to the estimation, modeling, and control algorithms, including a comprehensive simulation and testing environment.

Dynamic Design Lab Stanford, CA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT, PI: PROF. J. CHRISTIAN GERDES

Sep. 2009-Dec. 2018

- Collected, compiled, analyzed, and openly published vehicle dynamics data from highly-skilled professional race car drivers during live racing events to gain insights into vehicle control at the limits of handling. Compared human performance with autonomous vehicles to improve operating capabilities of active vehicle safety systems.
- Implemented autonomous vehicle control using drive-by-wire hardware and convex optimization software to operate at the handling limits while following a desired trajectory. Implemented and tested control algorithms on experimental vehicles using C and MATLAB.
- · Pioneered a comprehensive, noninvasive vehicle instrumentation suite for vintage race cars with significant historical value.
- Developed a graphical user interface in MATLAB for vehicle data visualization and exploratory data analysis.
- Assembled and maintained an end-to-end solution from surveyed GNSS base stations to on-board integrated navigation systems enabling
 research vehicles to operate reliably with centimeter-level position measurement accuracy. Installed and operated a Linux-based NTRIP
 caster to broadcast Differential GNSS corrections from multiple servers to multiple clients.

Stanford Department of Mechanical Engineering

Stanford, CA

SENIOR TEACHING ASSISTANT — MECHANICAL SYSTEMS DESIGN, PROFS. MARK CUTKOSKY AND PAUL MITIGUY

Jan.-Mar. 2016

- Developed curriculum and coordinated team of five other teaching assistants.
- · Led hands-on laboratory and tutorial sessions for course with 150 undergraduates exploring characteristics of machine elements.
- Advised design-project teams emphasizing the balance of physical and virtual prototyping based on engineering analysis.

Publications

JOURNAL ARTICLES

Vehicle control synthesis using phase portraits of planar dynamics

Carrie G. Bobier-Tiu, Craig E. Beal, John C. Kegelman, Rami Y. Hindiyeh, J. Christian Gerdes Vehicle System Dynamics 57.9 (2019) pp. 1318–1337. Taylor & Francis, 2019

7eriicie 3ysterii Dynamics 31.9 (2019) pp. 1316–1331. Taytoi & Francis, 2019

Neural network vehicle models for high-performance automated driving

Nathan A. Spielberg, Matthew Brown, Nitin R. Kapania, John C. Kegelman, J. Christian Gerdes

Science Robotics 4.28 (2019). Science Robotics, 2019

Insights into vehicle trajectories at the handling limits: analysing open data from race car drivers John C. Kegelman, Lene K. Harbott, J. Christian Gerdes

Vehicle System Dynamics 55.2 (2017) pp. 191–207. Taylor & Francis, 2017

PATENTS

Todd Christopher Klaus, Colleen Kelly Twitty, Stephen M. Erlien, John C. Kegelman, Charles A. Price, Austin Bennett Schuh, Joshua P. Switkes. "Distributed Safety Monitors for Automated Vehicles". U.S. pat. Peloton Technology Inc. Jan. 14, 2019.

Skills_

Programming C++, Python, MATLAB, C

Software Git, Bazel, MATLAB, Simulink, Linux, Mac OS X, Windows, Office, MoTeC i2